An adventure beyond words.
The Emoji Movie is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Tony Leondis.
Gene, a multi-expressional emoji, sets out on a
journey to become a normal emoji.
Gene (voice), played by T.J. Miller.
Hi-5 (voice), played by James Corden.
Jailbreak (voice), played by Anna Faris.
Smiler (voice), played by Maya Rudolph.
Mel Meh (voice), played by Steven Wright.
Mary Meh (voice), played by Jennifer Coolidge.
The Emoji Movie is a 2017 American animated comedy film based on emojis.
Produced by Columbia Pictures and Sony Pictures Animation, and distributed
by Sony Pictures Releasing, it stars the voices of T.J.
Miller, James Corden, Anna Faris, Maya Rudolph,
Steven Wright, Jennifer Coolidge, Jake T.
Austin, Christina Aguilera, Sofía Vergara, Sean Hayes, and Sir Patrick Stewart.
The film centers on a multi-expressional emoji, Gene (Miller), who exists in a digital city called Textopolis, for a smartphone owned by Alex (Austin),
embarking on a journey to become a normal emoji capable of only a single expression, accompanied by his friends, Hi-5 (Corden) and Jailbreak (Faris).
During their travels through the other apps, the trio must save their world
from total destruction before it is reset for functionality.
The film was directed by Tony Leondis from a screenplay he co-wrote with Eric
Siegel and Mike White, based on a story by Leondis and Siegel.
Inspired by Leondis' love of Toy Story (1995), the film was fast tracked into production in July 2015 after the bidding
war and the project was officially announced in April 2016, originally titled EmojiMovie: Express Yourself.
Most of the lead cast members were hired throughout the rest of the year.
The Emoji Movie had a production time of two years,
shorter than most other animated films.
The marketing of the film drew a negative response from the public
and an internet backlash, before the film's release.
The film held its premiere at the Regency Village Theatre on July 23, 2017, before being
theatrically released in the United States four days later on July 28.
It was a box-office success, grossing $217.8 million
worldwide against a $50 million production budget.
However, it was panned by critics who criticized its plot, writing, humor, voice-acting, tonal inconsistencies, use of product placement, and a lack of innovation, with
several critics deeming it inferior to other animated productions including Wreck-It Ralph (2012), The Lego Movie (2014), Inside Out (2015), among others.
At the 38th Golden Raspberry Awards, the film won four of its five nominations, including Worst
Picture, making it the first animated film to win in its respective categories.
It is frequently ranked as the worst film of 2017, and is regularly
seen as among the worst animated films of all time.
The film explores themes of villain, parody, 3d animation, emoji.
The tone is lighthearted.